<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="HTMLTemplateRenderer" inherits="Reference">
	<brief_description>
		A class that can parse and render HTML using a simple templating language.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		A class that can parse and render HTML using a simple templating language.
		This class uses a templating syntax like: [code]{{ EXPRESSION }}[/code]. Everything inbetween [code]{{ }}[/code] is an expression that the system will replace during rendering with actual values from a passed in Dictionary.
		Available expressions:
		{{ &lt;expr&gt; }}: Print escaped. Whatever is returned by expr gets printed and html excaped (except if the outer expression is a built-in print expression like p, pr, pb, pbr, qpr, qprb, vf, vfr, qvfr. etc. these methods do their own escapes and have special handling for backwards compatibility). Null turns into an empty string.
		{{# &lt;expr&gt; }}: Supress. Runs expression, no output.
		{{; &lt;expr&gt; }}: Force escaped. Always prints the result of the expression as escaped html. Null turns into an empty string.
		{{% &lt;expr&gt; }} Print raw. Always prints the result of the expression as raw unescaped html. Null turns into an empty string.
		{{if &lt;bool expr&gt; }} ... html ... {{elif &lt;bool expr&gt; }} ... html ... {{else}} ... html ... {{endif}}: if / else / elif / endif.
		{{for &lt;variable declaration&gt; in &lt;collection&gt; }} ... html ... {{endfor}}: Foreach.
		{{ /* .... comment ... */ }} or {{ /* }} ... {{ */ }}: Comments. Cannot be nested.
		Assuming you pass in the following Dictionary to [method render]:
		[code]var d : Dictionary = {
			"var": VALUE,
			"var1": VALUE,
			"var2": VALUE,
			"var_dict": {
				"x": VALUE
			},
			"var_arr": [
				VALUE,
			]
		}[/code]
		0. To escape [code]{{[/code] use: [code]{\{[/code].  [code]{\\{[/code] will turn into [code]{\{[/code] etc.
		1. [code]p(var)[/code] - print, escaped, also includes to string cast.
		2. [code]{{ var }}[/code] - equivalent to [code]p(var)[/code].
		3. [code](var)[/code] - equivalent to [code]p(var)[/code].
		4. [code]pr(var)[/code] - print_raw, not escaped, also includes a cast to string.
		5. [code]pb(var)[/code] - print_newline_to_br, escaped, turns newlines into br tags, also includes a to string cast.
		6. [code]prb(var)[/code] - print_raw_newline_to_br, not escaped, turns newlines into br tags, also includes a to string cast.
		7. [code]vf("%d %d", var1, var2)[/code] - vformat or snprintf or String fromatting using % in gdscript. Escaped.
		8. [code]vfr("%d %d", var1, var2)[/code] - vformat or snprintf or String fromatting using % in gdscript. Not Escaped.
		9. [code]qp(var1, var2)[/code] -  Same as p, but only prints when it's first argument evaluates to true. (First arg is not printed!)
		10. [code]qpr(var1, var2)[/code] - Same as pr, but only prints when it's first argument evaluates to true. (First arg is not printed!)
		11. [code]qpb(var1, var2)[/code] - Same as pb, but only prints when it's first argument evaluates to true. (First arg is not printed!)
		12. [code]qprb(var1, var2)[/code] - Same as prb, but only prints when it's first argument evaluates to true. (First arg is not printed!)
		13. [code]qvf(var1, "%d %d", var1, var2)[/code] - Same as vf, but only prints when it's first argument evaluates to true. Escaped. (First arg is not printed!)
		14. [code]qvfr(var1, "%d %d", var1, var2)[/code] - Same as vf, but only prints when it's first argument evaluates to true. Not escaped. (First arg is not printed!)
		15. [code]p(var_arr[0])[/code] - Array indexing.
		16. [code]p(var_dict["x"]), p(var_dict[x]), p(var_dict['x'])[/code] - Dictionary indexing.
		17. [code]p(var1, var2)[/code] - All methods supports multiple arguments.
		18. Let's say [code]var1[/code] is a [Vector3], [code]var["x"][/code] and [code]var[0][/code] work.
		19. Indexing will also call [code]get()[/code] on [Object]s.
		20. [code]p(var[var[var[2]]])[/code] Recursive indexing.
		21. Method calls on object that are passed in.
		22. Array creation: [ 1, 2, 3, 4 ]
		23. Dictionary creation: { "key1": "val1", "key2": "val2" }
		24. exists("varname"): Returns whether the given variable is set.
		25. approx_equals(var1, var2): Returns whether the 2 variables are approximately equal.
		26. setvar("varname", value): Sets variable's value in the input dictionary.
		27. setvar_if(expr, "varname", value): Sets variable's value in the input dictionary, if expr evaluates to true.
		28. getvar("varname"): Returns varname's value or null.
		29. getvar("varname", default_value): Returns varname's value, or the default given.
		30. range(to): Creates an iterator that goes from 0 to to.
		31. range(from, to): Creates an iterator that goes from from to to.
		32. range(from, to, step): Creates an iterator that goes from from to to by step.
		33. keys(some_dict): Returns the keys from the given dictionary as an array.
		34. values(some_dict): Returns the values from the given dictionary as an array.
		35. tr("key"): Retrieves a translation from the TranslationServer.
		36. trt("key", "locale"): Retrieves a translation from the TranslationServer.
		37. select(expr, val1, val2): If expr evaluates to true, then it returns val1, else it returns val2.
		38. int(), float(), str(): Conversion methods.
		39. Any variant can also be constructed: Vector2, Vector3, Transform ...
		40. Methods on variants can also be called: "str".strip_edges() ...
		So this is how your HTML will look like: [code]... HTML markup ... {{ p(var) }} ... {{ pr(var) }} ... {{ pb(var) }} ... {{ prb(var, var2) }} ... {{ vf("%d %d", var1, var2) }} ... etc.[/code]
		Note: For a different approach to generating HTML, you can also take a look at [HTMLBuilder].
		Note: In the old language this also worked: [code]var[x][/code], where x is supposed to be a string. This doesn't work anymore, as with the current feature set this would be very error prone, and confusing.
		Note: In the old language vf and qvf were always in raw print mode. This was likely not a good idea, so a raw version now also exists from them. Either search and replate to those, or use raw print mode with {{% }}.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="compile">
			<return type="bool" />
			<argument index="0" name="text" type="String" />
			<argument index="1" name="start_line" type="int" default="1" />
			<argument index="2" name="show_error" type="bool" default="false" />
			<description>
				Compile the given template. Returns true if an error happened.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_compile_error_str" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="String" />
			<description>
				Returns the compile error string (if any).
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_template_text" qualifiers="const">
			<return type="String" />
			<description>
				Returns the template text.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="render">
			<return type="HTMLTemplateRenderResult" />
			<argument index="0" name="data" type="Dictionary" />
			<argument index="1" name="p_show_error" type="bool" default="false" />
			<description>
				Render the template using the data dictionary as it's inputs.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
	<constants>
	</constants>
</class>
